<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Philosopher, Classical Teacher, Writer</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:09:54 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:09:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keith Got a Job in CA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://parks.lacounty.gov/wps/wcm/connect/7b7d5069-f3da-4a61-9088-d15af9daf9b6/Castaic+Lake+crop.jpg?MOD=AJPERES&amp;amp;CACHEID=7b7d5069-f3da-4a61-9088-d15af9daf9b6&quot; alt=&quot;Header Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear friends and family,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your prayers, encouragement, and well-wishes. Lindsay and I are happy to report that God has answered with a full-time job at Trinity Classical Academy in Valencia  (just north of LA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be teaching some fun subjects like Roman history, writing, rhetoric, and ancient Greek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trinity is a wonderful private school, offering a challenging K-12 classical education. They employ a half dozen other PhDs already, lead by a crackerjack team of administrators. Graduates are attending Berkeley, Princeton, and other good schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, this is truly a “dream job”. We’ll be about an hour and a half from family in the OC. Josiah will be able to attend kindergarten when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re so grateful to take this new step in my career as a classical teacher and to put this PhD to good use introducing the next generation to the best of western civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bit-of-back-story&quot;&gt;A bit of back story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ameristudent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/NorthPark0783_00789-EDIT.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;trinity&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, I applied to work at Trinity. However, I was also applying to graduate schools at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve know the school for many years and always admired the work they do. Though I opted for graduate school then, I asked them if I came back with a PhD if that would be a plus or a minus. They said that’d be great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m done with graduate school (Dr. Buhler, at your service!) I applied to 50 places, both college and high school jobs. I got three “requests for more information” from colleges but no offers. I got 2 job offers from classical high schools. One was in Virginia, which was a great opportunity but far from family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked Trinity, one more time, if they had an opening. They said they did! I jumped at the chance to visit and interview &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;. They flew me out and it was a wonderful visit. I did a guest teaching lesson and talked for hours with the leadership, faculty, staff, even students and parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They offered a full-time job doing something I love and great potential for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to deliberate for about 30 seconds before we said yes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we are sad to be leaving our home and second family in Kentucky. Wilmore has been the small-town America that I did not know still existed and only dreamed of living in. I will miss the four seasons, the fireflies in summer, the snow in winter, the endless acres of luscious green horse farms, the scenic drives, and the Southern hospitality of the people here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also miss my colleagues and students at the University and church family who have made this truly a second home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife bore our two children here, and we have spent five of our seven years of marriage here. But the season is coming to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are packing up and getting ready for another cross country move, this time back to Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We leave in June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll spend July in California with family, and move to Santa Clarita area (possibly Castaic)  to commence school in August.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/job/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/job/</guid>
        
        <category>life updates</category>
        
        <category>buhlers</category>
        
        
        <category>Academia</category>
        
        <category>Classical education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life is Suffering, and Other Jordan Peterson Quotes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/jordanbpeterson.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/jordan-smaller-size-bw.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&quot; alt=&quot;header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Life is suffering.
Love is the desire to see unnecessary suffering ameliorated.
Truth is the handmaiden of love. 
Dialogue is the pathway to truth. 
Humility is recognition of personal insufficiency and the willingness to learn. 
To learn is to die voluntarily and be born again, in great ways and small. 
Speech must be untrammelled so that dialogue can take place; so that we can all humbly learn, so that truth can serve love, so that suffering can be ameliorated, so that we can all stumble forward to the kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4twXmX7IjXY&quot;&gt;Apr. 24, 2017. Hosted by the Young Americans For Liberty chapter at Linfield College as part of the Speak Freely Series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/gkYy30g.png&quot; alt=&quot;peterson 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In order to speak what you regard as the truth, you have to let go of the outcome. You have to think, “OK, I’m going to say way I think. Stupid as I am, biased as I am, ignorant as I am, I’m going to state what I think as clearly as I can. And I’m going to live with the consequences no matter what they are.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JDvj6DQd93o&quot;&gt;Nov 19th 2016. The debate at the University of Toronto Faculty of Arts &amp;amp; Science Forum examining Bill C-16 and the Ontario Human Rights Code h. Between Prof Jordan B Peterson on one side and Dr Brenda Cossman/Dr Mary K Bryson on the other; Debate moderated by Prof Mayo Moran &amp;amp; foreword by David Cameron Dean of the Faculty of Arts &amp;amp; Science.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Without Christianity, and its emphasis on truth at all costs, science would never have come about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WJSJcPKA1Ug&quot;&gt;May 5, 2017, the Rubin Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/25/jordan-peterson-quotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/25/jordan-peterson-quotes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Philosophy</category>
        
        <category>Academia</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Petitio or Non-Sequitur</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.psychologytoday.com/sites/default/files/blogs/67492/2013/06/127024-126515.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to write a philosophy book one day trying to show that a very tiny minority of arguments validly derive their conclusion from true premises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working title: Petitio or Non-Sequitur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thesis would be simply this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most philosophical or rational arguments beg the question, placing a modified version of the conclusion somewhere in the premises; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most scientific or empirical arguments commit a non sequitur, merely asserting a new conclusion ex nihilo after detailing true but ultimately unrelated premises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if this these warrants a whole book, because now that I’ve said it – that’s pretty much the whole book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/23/petitio-non-sequitur/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/23/petitio-non-sequitur/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Philosophy</category>
        
        <category>Academia</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dissertation Reflections</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.keithbuhler.com/images/defense.png&quot; alt=&quot;header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some of you know, I recently completed my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keithbuhler.com/phd&quot;&gt;dissertation&lt;/a&gt;. It took me four and a half years from admission to completion, though I will formally graduate this May. This was, apparently, a kind of record in our department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to reflect a bit about the experience and hear from you about yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;timing&quot;&gt;Timing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dissertation writing process took me about 14 months. The “research” phase was ongoing; not only during the writing but long before writing all of the research I had been doing for classes or out of personal interest was leading me toward my thesis and the strategy for formulating it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was told that in, in humanities, in an ideal world, you research for (about) a year and write for (about) a year. So in two years you can have your dissertation done. I was also told, however, that it’s more important that it be done than that it be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;focus&quot;&gt;Focus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two years after since my daughter was born (Dec 27, 2014 - Dec 2016) were busier than ever in my life before. I dealt with some serious anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety can cripple productivity of course, but it can also stifle procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly, anxiety is a great motivator to get to work and stay on task. I’ve also come to suspect that I have low-level ADD, which comes with some benefits: hyperattentiveness. When I sat down to write, I wrote a lot and wrote for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I wrote 1-page a day for 14 months, I ended up with well over 400 pages of notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;committees&quot;&gt;Committees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dissertating is notoriously solitary work. You are the protagonist and the antagonist. Man versus wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at some point, suddenly, your primary task is to get a committee together to read and criticize your dissertation. They were all very cooperative, but it was a massive change of pace to try and coordinate the schedules of five busy professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, one committee member had to leave because they were not available in the Fall, when I needed to defend. Another committee member had to leave to take a job near his fiance. That left two vacancies that needed filling on short notice. Thankfully, three generous folks stepped up to the plate and agreed to serve last minute – though only two were needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;job-applications&quot;&gt;Job Applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardly before the ink is dried, one must begin explaining one’s research to a broader audience. This is the “research statement” that affixes to many job applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending a year (or many years) disciplining oneself to communicate in language that is specific, nuanced, careful, clear, and precisely technical, one must immediately discipline oneself to speak in language that is clear, easy, forceful, and broadly accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;defense&quot;&gt;Defense&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defense was inevitably a bit nerve wracking. There are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=edQv9OKvfdU&quot;&gt;good resources&lt;/a&gt; online to help you prepare, in addition to informative coaching from recent graduates of your program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People rarely “fail” – the goal is not just to pass but to pass well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote some notes, reminders, and re-read portions of my dissertation (if I don’t have it pretty well memorized now, I never will!) and went into the defense confident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It last about 2 hours, and I thought it was a roaring good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-reflections&quot;&gt;Your reflections&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did your dissertation writing go? How did you keep focus? What other trials did you face with your committee and/or defense?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/13/dissertation-reflections/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/13/dissertation-reflections/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Philosophy</category>
        
        <category>Academia</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Case-by-Case Consideration of Weird Views</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://48hcc.nz/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Overton_Window-1024x538.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Header Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my students have “crazy” views. Then again, I have some crazy views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, is it possible to dismiss all strange, unusual, “extreme” or weird views at once? Or must one examine them case-by-case?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my part, I try to consider each weird view individually. So far as possible, given time constraints, I try to judge “weird” views (bigfoot, fairies, UFOs, ghosts, demons) one by one, examining its individual merits rather than judging the whole set at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I try to judge all “official” views (western science, religious monotheism, political democracy) one by one rather than accepting the whole set at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call this ‘case-by-case epistemology.’ Keep your “Overton window” huge, with narrow slices of “unthinkable” views on the sides. The wide range alternatives to present policy are all fair game, even if they seem ‘weird’ at first, so long as there are arguments to support the view that can survive scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case-by-case approach to weird views doesn’t mean you are confused.  I am a persuaded Christian, Platonist, rationalist, traditionalist, conservative with fairly thought-out views about religion, politics, morality, metaphysics, epistemology, ethics and so on. What it means is that I do see intrinsic value in remaining willing to hear out both (or multiple) sides of an issue and take it case-by-case. As I read him, that willingness is how Plato’s Socrates lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I take atheism seriously. And pantheism. I take ethical egoism seriously. And moral nihilism. I take the politically progressive or so-called culturally Marxist ideology seriously. And anarchism. And monarchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.energyenhancement.org/Rembrandt-Aristotle-contemplating-bust-Homer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;aristotle rembrandt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major benefit of this approach is relational: when I converse with people with “strange” views in class or in church or the proverbial water cooler, I enjoy the discourse and try to learn something, and criticize their views charitably. (They usually find my arguments delightful, if exotic, as well.) And converse I do. In the last five years in class and work and life, I have come across conspiracy theorists, flat earthers, Tarot card readers, anarchists, alt-right, Russian Orthodox Christians, scientific atheists, Nietzschean nihilists, a person who lives in a haunted house, prophets and miracle workers, religious nuns, religious “Nones”, and others. With each person, I strive to &lt;em&gt;really dialogue&lt;/em&gt; – to listen and to talk. I strive to take their thoughts seriously, to disagree without condescension, and generally to have a roaring good time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To dismiss views because they are weird is oftentimes a genetic fallacy (how could anything good come from X?) or a fallacy of appeal to personal credulity (how could anything be true that strikes me as odd?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second major benefit is intellectual.  I have learned a lot and had to think a lot harder about my metaphysics and epistemology. Why, for example, if I take eye-witness testimony to be authoritative in most cases, do I believe X when he reports A but not Y when he reports B – even of both are non-experts but personal friends whom I trust?  If universals are not real, then why do arguments for nominalism assume realism in the very form of the language? If democratic involvement is so essential for liberty why does less than half the U.S. population vote?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even learn something talking to conspiracy theorists. A lot of such theories affirm conjecture when agnosticism would work just as well. But I still debate them (for at time!).  And if their bad arguments challenge me to come up with good arguments, it’s not a waste of time to debate. It’s like swinging a bat with weights on it – it’s “unnecessary” work, but has a payoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upl.stack.com/wp-content/uploads/Do-Donuts-Improve-Bat-Speed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;bat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, how do you &lt;em&gt;disprove&lt;/em&gt; an unprovable theory? Here’s one way: assume that people are tremendously bad at keeping secrets. By this hypothesis, any alleged conspiracy that involved intimate knowledge of more than 5 would eventually be leaked, on purpose or on accident, and become publicly known. Any alleged event (such as a fake moon landing) that would have required the secrecy of more than 5 people did not happen. Some small conspiracies are not automatically disproved by this argument, but many large ones are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For whatever this argument’s merits, it’s the kind of thought I only had because of talking to the conspiracy folks and refusing to dismiss their weird views with ad hominems or bullying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A third benefit is moral: I have to cultivate and exercise virtues such as charity, the benefit of the doubt, and undying patience. The dialectic grinds slowly, but it grinds effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major downside is it takes a long time. It is much quicker to categorize views according to “families” and develop a well-reasoned position about all “theisms” or all “atheisms” all at once. But the danger of mis-categorization makes the extra time worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I go out of my way to research radical views all the time. Rather, when I come across people who hold radical views, each one gets a full and hopefully fair hearing. ANd a hearing takes more time than a sneering. Chesterton says (in &lt;em&gt;Dumb Ox&lt;/em&gt;) of Thomas Aquinas that he refused to sneer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It is generally the man who is not ready to argue, who is ready to sneer. That is why, in recent literature, there has been so little argument and so much sneering.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second downside is that people think &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; hold the weird views I’m just entertaining. For example, I had an argument with a close friend about the “alt-right” this last election cycle. I am not alt-right, if I understand the term, but he was trying to define ‘alt-right’ as ‘evil’ and thus demand a disavowel. I’m still trying to understand what the term means and get a correct definition, so I was trying not to dismiss those who identify that way with simple epithets. He assumed my refusal to disavow them amounted to an endorsement. It is unfortunate, but inevitable, that sometimes people will &lt;em&gt;demand&lt;/em&gt; you affirm or deny something you haven’t decided on. I take this demand to be (sometimes at least) mere bullying, so you’d have to resist and put up with being misunderstood, insulted, or slandered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another downside is that I don’t get to feel arrogant. I don’t automatically presume that I’m the intellectual superior to everyone who disagrees with me. I don’t presume that you’re either stupid-and-wrong or intelligent-and-right but assume that some people are intelligent-but-wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a big loss, because it’s fun to feel superior. But so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there any other downsides I’m missing?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/07/overton-windows-biting-bullets/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/07/overton-windows-biting-bullets/</guid>
        
        <category>Overton window</category>
        
        <category>epistemology</category>
        
        <category>weird views</category>
        
        
        <category>Philosophy</category>
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raise Minimum Wage, Raise Unemployment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://thelibertycaucus.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/henry-hazlitt-economics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Header Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question – &lt;a href=&quot;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2951110&quot;&gt;Why is it that, according to Harvard Business School, minimum wage hikes don’t hurt 5-star restaurants but do shut down restaurants that employ and serve low-income Americans?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer – basic economics. Increasing minimum wage has always, and will always, increase unemployment, by the iron laws of cause and effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An illuminating discussion from &lt;a href=&quot;https://mises.org/system/tdf/Henry%20Hazlitt%20Economics%20in%20One%20Lesson.pdf?file=1&amp;amp;type=document&quot;&gt;Henry Hazlit, &lt;em&gt;Economics in One Lesson&lt;/em&gt; Chapter 18:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The first thing that happens when a law is passed that no one shall be paid less than $30 for a forty-hour week is that no one who is not worth $30 a week to an employer will be employed at all. You cannot make a man worth a given amount by making it illegal for anyone to offer him anything less. You merely deprive him of the right to earn the amount that his abilities and situation would permit him to earn, while you deprive the community even of the moderate services that he is capable of rendering. In brief, for a low wage you substitute unemployment. You do harm all around, with no comparable compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hazlit continues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It may be thought that if the law forces the payment of a higher wage in a given industry, that industry can then charge higher prices for its product, so that the burden of paying the higher wage is merely shifted to consumers. Such shifts, however, are not easily made, nor are the consequences of artificial wage raising so easily escaped. A higher price for the product may not be possible: it may merely drive consumers to some substitute. Or, if consumers continue to buy the product of the industry in which wages have been raised, the higher price will cause them to buy less of it. While some workers in the industry will be benefited from the higher wage, therefore, others will be thrown out of employment altogether. On the other hand, if the price of the product is not raised, marginal producers in the industry will be driven out of business; so that reduced production and consequent unemployment will merely be brought about in another way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lest he appear to be advocating for low wages, Hazlit clarifies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All this is not to argue that there is no way of raising wages. It is merely to point out that the apparently easy method of raising them by government fiat is the wrong way and the worst way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hazlit’s &lt;em&gt;Economics in One Lesson&lt;/em&gt; is well worth reading, especially for beginners like myself. The “lesson” is that we must study all the effects of an action for all people, not just short-term effects for some people. He says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Economics, as we have now seen again and again, is a science of recognizing secondary consequences. It is also a science of seeing general consequences. It is the science of tracing the effects of some proposed or existing policy not only on some special interest in the short run, but on the general interest in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/06/minimum-wage-unemployment/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/06/minimum-wage-unemployment/</guid>
        
        <category>economics</category>
        
        <category>money</category>
        
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Fathers Feel about Their Babies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/originals/f0/5a/ed/f05aed3c4a6706923852b36b165290bb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Header Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My best friend and his wife are having their first baby next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked about how he doesn’t feel anything about “being a father” yet. I felt the same absence of feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moms and dads react differently to newborn babies, especially the first baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s the passage from Tolstoy’s &lt;em&gt;Anna Karenina&lt;/em&gt; that says it all. I reproduce that passage here for your edification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is about Kittie, from Part 8 Chapter 6, the second is about Levin, from Chapter 18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kitties-motherhood-chapter-6&quot;&gt;Kittie’s motherhood, Chapter 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I must run to Mitya. As ill-luck would have it, I haven’t fed him since tea. He’s awake now, and sure to be screaming.” And feeling a rush of milk, she hurried to the nursery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not a mere guess; her connection with the child was still so close, that she could gauge by the flow of her milk his need of food, and knew for certain he was hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She knew he was crying before she reached the nursery. And he was indeed crying. She heard him and hastened. But the faster she went, the louder he screamed. It was a fine healthy scream, hungry and impatient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Has he been screaming long, nurse, very long?” said Kitty hurriedly, seating herself on a chair, and preparing to give the baby the breast. “But give me him quickly. Oh, nurse, how tiresome you are! There, tie the cap afterwards, do!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baby’s greedy scream was passing into sobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But you can’t manage so, ma’am,” said Agafea Mihalovna, who was almost always to be found in the nursery. “He must be put straight. A-oo! a-oo!” she chanted over him, paying no attention to the mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nurse brought the baby to his mother. Agafea Mihalovna followed him with a face dissolving with tenderness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He knows me, he knows me. In God’s faith, Katerina Alexandrovna, ma’am, he knew me!” Agafea Mihalovna cried above the baby’s screams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Kitty did not hear her words. Her impatience kept growing, like the baby’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their impatience hindered things for a while. The baby could not get hold of the breast right, and was furious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last, after despairing, breathless screaming, and vain sucking, things went right, and mother and child felt simultaneously soothed, and both subsided into calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But poor darling, he’s all in perspiration!” said Kitty in a whisper, touching the baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What makes you think he knows you?” she added, with a sidelong glance at the baby’s eyes, that peered roguishly, as she fancied, from under his cap, at his rhythmically puffing cheeks, and the little red-palmed hand he was waving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Impossible! If he knew anyone, he would have known me,” said Kitty, in response to Agafea Mihalovna’s statement, and she smiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She smiled because, though she said he could not know her, in her heart she was sure that he knew not merely Agafea Mihalovna, but that he knew and understood everything, and knew and understood a great deal too that no one else knew, and that she, his mother, had learned and come to understand only through him. To Agafea Mihalovna, to the nurse, to his grandfather, to his father even, Mitya was a living being, requiring only material care, but for his mother he had long been a mortal being, with whom there had been a whole series of spiritual relations already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When he wakes up, please God, you shall see for yourself. Then when I do like this, he simply beams on me, the darling! Simply beams like a sunny day!” said Agafea Mihalovna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, well; then we shall see,” whispered Kitty. “But now go away, he’s going to sleep.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;levins-fatherhood-part-8-chapter-18&quot;&gt;Levin’s Fatherhood, Part 8, Chapter 18:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitty was standing with her sleeves tucked up over the baby in the bath. Hearing her husband’s footstep, she turned towards him, summoning him to her with her smile. With one hand she was supporting the fat baby that lay floating and sprawling on its back, while with the other she squeezed the sponge over him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come, look, look!” she said, when her husband came up to her. “Agafea Mihalovna’s right. He knows us!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitya had on that day given unmistakable, incontestable signs of recognizing all his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as Levin approached the bath, the experiment was tried, and it was completely successful. The cook, sent for with this object, bent over the baby. He frowned and shook his head disapprovingly. Kitty bent down to him, he gave her a beaming smile, propped his little hands on the sponge and chirruped, making such a queer little contented sound with his lips, that Kitty and the nurse were not alone in their admiration. Levin, too, was surprised and delighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baby was taken out of the bath, drenched with water, wrapped in towels, dried, and after a piercing scream, handed to his mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, I am glad you are beginning to love him,” said Kitty to her husband, when she had settled herself comfortably in her usual place, with the baby at her breast. “I am so glad! It had begun to distress me. You said you had no feeling for him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No; did I say that? I only said I was disappointed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What! disappointed in him?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not disappointed in him, but in my own feeling; I had expected more. I had expected a rush of new delightful emotion to come as a surprise. And then instead of that—disgust, pity…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She listened attentively, looking at him over the baby, while she put back on her slender fingers the rings she had taken off while giving Mitya his bath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And most of all, at there being far more apprehension and pity than pleasure. Today, after that fright during the storm, I understand how I love him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kitty’s smile was radiant.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/05/fathers-feel-about-babies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/05/fathers-feel-about-babies/</guid>
        
        <category>fathers</category>
        
        <category>babies</category>
        
        
        <category>Culture</category>
        
        <category>Relationships</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>There is One Learning Style</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.licdn.com/mpr/mpr/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAkKAAAAJDE2ZjYxNDVkLTAzNjgtNGM2My1hYWE3LWU0ZWVlZjNhMmY3Ng.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Header Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Classical teachers are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keithbuhler.com/buhlerreport/philosophy/2016/07/26/wealth-and-wisdom.html&quot;&gt;wealthy with wisdom&lt;/a&gt;. This embarrassment of riches allows us to be a bit shrewd about fads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we hate to say “I told you so,” it is hard to avoid when fad after fad turns out to be empty when compared to the simple, plain, and hard truths of educational method: use language a lot, read a lot, think a lot, &lt;a href=&quot;http://literacy.rice.edu/thirty-million-word-gap&quot;&gt;talk a lot&lt;/a&gt;, write a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus supplement to the above: Read the hardest and best books you can find, think as hard as you can, write as much as you can, and you will be in the top 1% of educated folks around. Nothing else can replace these simple, solid, painfully true truths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus bonus supplement: It’s parents job; teachers can only supplement learning in the home…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast to these rules, the latest fad sells you an appealing but ultimately crazy quick fix – such as that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/local/lanow/la-me-ln-la-unified-ipad-settlement-20150925-story.html&quot;&gt;iPads are going to somehow bring up test scores.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest instance of pointless panaceas is “learning styles.” I’m glad I’ve never tried to figure out my learning style other than anecdotally (“I learn well from audio books. You don’t? Huh. Fancy that.”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some &lt;a href=&quot;http://thefederalist.com/2017/03/22/brain-scientists-learning-styles-like-auditory-visual-and-kinesthetic-are-bunk/&quot;&gt;recent research suggests&lt;/a&gt; that maybe learning styles are not really a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe panaceas made with 100% snake oil should be ignored as a category, rather than believed/debunked one by one. To quote John Mark Reynolds circa 2000:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Read a lot, write a lot, discuss a lot. Everything else is a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/02/learning-styles-are-bunk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/02/learning-styles-are-bunk/</guid>
        
        <category>learning styles</category>
        
        
        <category>Classical education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A recent chapter on Deification</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://trinities.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/TheosAgape-e1444308929206.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Header Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.academia.edu/30578073/Becoming_Gods_Deification_and_the_Supernatural&quot;&gt;David Litwa provides a fascinating (and to my mind accurate) survey of deification.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His article clarifies what the notion of “becoming god” amounts to, and explains the various species of deifiction: political deification, deification through beauty, deification as magic, deification as imitation, Christian deification, self-deification, deification through Gnosticism. This is all historically informative and very interesting; the kicker is that he accurately covers our own fashionable form of deification: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keithbuhler.com/buhlerreport/singularity-chalmers&quot;&gt;techno-deification.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Litwa’s article is a fascinating peek into human nature and will &lt;del&gt;instantly transform you into a god&lt;/del&gt; illuminate you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/01/deification/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/04/01/deification/</guid>
        
        <category>deification</category>
        
        <category>theology</category>
        
        <category>transhumanism</category>
        
        <category>singularity</category>
        
        
        <category>Academia</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Self-loathing poster child displays self-loathing posters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.innsight.com/1/assets/themes/berkeleyinn/images/Berkeley-Campinele.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Header Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a only a few weeks ago that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-macdonald-berkeley-victimology-20170207-story.html&quot;&gt;UC Berkeley descended into a riotous hotbed of anarchy.&lt;/a&gt; Leftists at Berkeley repressed free speech, vandalized public property, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CIFYTYNl7ng&quot;&gt;assaulted innocents.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Meanwhile, where outright violence failed, Berkeley’s foil has been taken down by conservatives who were not happy with his being welcomed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cpac.conservative.org/&quot;&gt;CPAC&lt;/a&gt; and being, ipso facto, welcomed into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalreview.com/article/445114/milo-phenomenon-understanding-right-wing-rage&quot;&gt;the intellectual conservative movement.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether the same self-destructive provocateur will rise from the ashes remains to be seen…  What is clear is that Berkeley’s own decline has reached rock bottom ideological incoherence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berkeley loathes itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has become the kind of place that spends $20 million annually on diversity in order to decrease diversity. It has become the kind of place that violently imposes inclusiveness that excludes conservative, rural, religious, or traditional voices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has become the kind of place that pushes its social justice utopianism so far that not only Red State Texans but also Left Coast leftists are berated for falling short of utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berkeley is so pure that Berkeley hates itself for being impure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-inequality-and-exclusion-office&quot;&gt;The Inequality and Exclusion Office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest example of berating oneself for imperfection are these posters. Take a look at the poster here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.squarespace.com/static/52a8f573e4b0ed42f38a0199/t/589383335016e1dcf16422f2/1486062438299/?format=750w&quot; alt=&quot;risible&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;LA Times&lt;/em&gt; explains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;UC Berkeley’s Division of Equity and Inclusion has placed vertical banners across the main campus reminding students of the contemporary university’s paramount mission: assigning guilt and innocence within the ruthlessly competitive hierarchy of victimhood. Each banner shows a photo of a student or a member of the student-services bureaucracy, beside a purported quotation from that student or bureaucrat. No rolling cadences here, no exhortations to intellectual conquest. Instead, just whining or penitential snippets from the academic lexicon of identity politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Read the rest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-macdonald-berkeley-victimology-20170207-story.html&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the posters drive home the revelation that being a non-white non-cis non-male is longer enough to satisfy the social justice nannies. Gone are the days when a female Asian could safely assume she contributed to diversity simply by existing. Now she has to (smile and) “acknowledge how power and privilege intersect” in her daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Um, OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/MicMedia/videos/1386008451421941/&quot;&gt;all white people are racist&lt;/a&gt;, but even people of color, women, LGBTQ+ people who are otherwise high the hierarchy are not safe. For example…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you &lt;a href=&quot;http://theadipositivityproject.zenfolio.com/about.html&quot;&gt;celebrate fat people, you might still be promoting white privilege.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you &lt;a href=&quot;http://everydayfeminism.com/2016/09/social-justice-activism-ableist/&quot;&gt;work for social justice activism, you might still be  ableist.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/a-letter-to-open-minded-genuinely-kind-educated_us_58404ebce4b0b93e10f8dffc&quot;&gt;advocate for feminism, you might not be intersectional enough.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deathandtaxesmag.com/280129/beyonce-capitalism-black-activism/&quot;&gt;advocate for black feminism, you might still be  exploiting the poor.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k5GYlZKfBmI&amp;amp;t=116s&quot;&gt;are gay or lesbian with a preference for one kind of genitals, you might still be transphobic.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whew… Imagine how hard you will have to work if you are low on the “competitive hierarchy of victimhood.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-this-the-bottom&quot;&gt;Is this the bottom?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are at least two takeaways from this story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, letting leftism run to its natural limit, we can see its natural incoherence. That incoherence is coded into its DNA from the beginning, but it comes to light at end-stage moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Berkeley is a pitri dish sample of &lt;a href=&quot;http://thefederalist.com/2015/01/06/have-we-already-reached-peak-leftism/&quot;&gt;peak leftism.&lt;/a&gt; They have carried out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marcuse.org/herbert/pubs/60spubs/65repressivetolerance.htm&quot;&gt;Herbert Marcuse’s recommendation in &lt;em&gt;Repressive Tolerance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of viciously excluding any but the most stringent leftist thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike even Harvard (Sandel) and Yale (George) which have token conservatives, Berkeley seems pretty well under the lockdown of the herding, conformity, and homogeneity.  As &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2n9t0GR&quot;&gt;Edwin Friedman&lt;/a&gt; says in &lt;em&gt;A Failure of Nerve&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Leaders in chronically anxious America today—whether they are black or white, Jewish or Christian, liberal or conservative, young or old, male or female—tend to support or adapt to the most incessantly demanding members of their following… And in some institutions the togetherness forces put such a premium on inclusivity that those who do not agree with making it the overriding principle of the organization are isolated or rejected, thus creating Orwellian “Animal Farms” in which diversity is eliminated in the name of diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By letting the poster child of social justice nihilism make posters, we can watch in real time as it cannibalizes itself. The social justice program amounts to the &lt;em&gt;political&lt;/em&gt; will to eradicate all &lt;em&gt;immorality&lt;/em&gt;, in oneself and others. But, as Roger Scruton points out in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fools-Frauds-Firebrands-Thinkers-Left/dp/1408187337&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thinkers of the New Left&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “The search for a policy to overcome original sin is not a coherent political project.” And and overcoming &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; original sin, even in the movement’s most devout members, is exactly the goal. Scruton continues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…the goal of ‘social justice’ is no longer equality before the law, or the equal claim to the rights of citizenship, as these were advocated at the Enlightenment. The goal is a comprehensive rearrangement of society, so that privileges, hierarchies, and even the unequal distribution of goods are either overcome or challenged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said that Berkeley has reached rock bottom.  On second thought, if this is as bad as it gets, perhaps Berkeley can recover after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dwell-on-the-good&quot;&gt;Dwell on the Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second take away is that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leabruno.com/blog/2017/2/2/extensive-portraiture-work-for-uc-berkeley&quot;&gt;Lea Bruno&lt;/a&gt;, the quite gifted photographer behind UCB’s self-contradicting and self-loathing propoganda, makes beautiful pictures. When detached from the incoherent and self-loathing labels, some of these portraits are worth enjoying.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/03/22/berkeley-poster-child-berate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog7-lessmore/2017/03/22/berkeley-poster-child-berate/</guid>
        
        <category>Berkeley</category>
        
        <category>SJWs</category>
        
        <category>progressivism</category>
        
        <category>cultural marxism</category>
        
        
        <category>Politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
